I want to tell you a story...
[echoing] Story... story...
About how the world ends...
[echoing] Ends... ends...
And the man from the future sent
back through time to stop it.
[dramatic notes]
Here, in the present day,
he uncovered a conspiracy:
men in the shadows
who sought to release
a plague upon the world.
They call themselves
the Army of the 12 Monkeys.
[roar]
But in the darkness, the man found hope:
a woman, a partner.
Together they fought to stop the plague,
but fate was not on their side...
for, you see, the man also
forged a bond with another,
someone he considered a brother.
If the man were to succeed
and change the future,
the brother's son would never be born,
so the brother turned his back on the man
and joined the enemy.
[gunshots]
The woman was wounded, dying in her time,
so to save her, the man sent her to his.
And in the end, because the
woman had taught him to love,
the man could not let his brother die.
Even though it was written,
the man broke that fate
and changed time.
Now, the time of the plague is upon us,
and the man and woman are
separated by oceans of time,
destined to never see one another again.
I told you,
this is the story of how the world ends,
one that begins at the end
and ends at the beginning...
a story that, like time itself,
can be changed.
[upbeat music]
- _
- ♪ Time is on my side ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ Time is on my side ♪
[tires squealing]
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
♪ ♪
[grunts]
[tires screech]
♪ ♪
[tires squealing]
[tires screeching]
♪ ♪
♪ Time is on my side ♪
♪ Yeah, yeah ♪
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Hello, Traveler.
[panting]
You almost had me in Shanghai.
London too.
You cannot run from fate.
Fortunately for us, you kept
poking your head aboveground.
[electronic beeping]
Let me ask you,
why is the Army of the 12
Monkeys trying to kill me?
Because your death is preordained.
You served your purpose.
Now the plague is imminent.
It was your guidance
that led us to the virus,
and for this we're grateful.
But now your cycle is complete.
So long, Traveler.
Now's a good time!
[boom!]
[gunshots]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
You all right?
That was cutting it close.
What are you talking
about? Timing was perfect.
They already had their guns drawn.
- Relax! You're alive.
- [scoffs]
He's such an old man now.
James Cole.
Nice to meet you. Where's the virus?
I see that both of you
are once again unified in purpose.
- Nah.
- Not really.
We just don't like you.
How we all feel about each other
is irrelevant in this moment,
because neither you nor your
friend will leave this bridge alive.
You're outnumbered.
[chuckles] How do you figure?
The Witness has spoken.
[engines revving]
Shit.
[automatic gunfire]
Go! Go!
[gunfire continues]
It was a good plan.
It coulda gone better.
[gunfire]
Nowhere to go.
Don't do that.
Don't do that!
Cole!
[water splashes]
♪ ♪
Shit.
[water splashes]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com
_
There's no sign of them.
None of this was foreseen.
We need to protect the virus.
Jennifer is taking too long.
I want you to shadow her personally.
That is not the will of the Witness.
Do it.
[sweeping music]
♪ ♪
You all right, old man?
Jacked up my arm.
At least you got a dose of
Jones's injections in you.
It'll help you heal faster
and age slower... mostly.
You know, these, uh...
old man jokes you keep saying...
[chuckles]
This gonna be, like, a running theme?
I think so.
I like it.
We're low on ammo.
Gonna need more if your
friends show up again.
They were never my friends.
That doesn't make it much better.
You know they're never gonna stop, right?
Witness knows the future.
They're always gonna be a step ahead.
You want to be running your whole life?
It's not about running.
Cassie's gone.
Maybe she made it to the future, maybe not.
It's up to me now to stop the virus.
That's right.
Save everyone.
Everyone except my son.
You know what?
Why don't you stop me then, huh?
Go ahead.
I'm waiting for it every
night I go to sleep.
Kill me; it'd be the
easiest thing in the world.
Listen, you believe in the past.
I believe in the future.
It is what it is.
We get free and clear of these guys,
we should split up.
- [scoffs]
- For good.
Make it harder on them, easier on us.
It's been three months.
You can't keep underground forever.
It's like she said...
the minute we poke our head up,
they're gonna find us.
They never found us in Berlin.
We were in the tunnels
the whole time there.
- We were underground.
- Right.
The 12 Monkeys might be
able to tell the future,
but that's not how they're finding us.
♪ ♪
They must have put a tracker in me.
We got to find someone who
can find it and cut it out,
some kind of back alley surgeon.
I know a guy across the Danube.
Worked with him at Markridge.
All right.
You stay here underground.
I'll go find him.
Once we get that out of you...
separate ways.
Hey.
I think she made it.
_
Ethan Seki.
That's Ramse.
Whoa, it's all right.
This is him. Do it, Cole.
I'm not doing anything.
Shoot him.
Cassie, put the gun down.
♪ ♪
- [gunfire]
- Cass!
What are you doing?
I'm sending you to Katarina.
[gasping]
Shh. You're all right.
Katarina.
I'm in the future.
Or the present, depending
on your point of view.
- How long?
- Four days.
The bullet wound.
You...
Yes, crudely.
I'm afraid surgery is not my strong suit.
Well, I'm here.
That's something.
Yes, but why are you here, Dr. Railly?
We tracked Ramse to Project Splinter.
Mr. Ramse?
He was working for the
Army of the 12 Monkeys
as their advisor for decades.
You stopped him?
Cole wouldn't do it.
When it comes to Mr. Ramse, his
judgment has always been... unreliable.
I shot Ramse.
I imagine that was quite difficult for you,
being a doctor.
- It wasn't.
- That's good.
Grieving over who we were
only gets in the way of
who we need to become.
[footsteps]
Those men out there in the hoods...
who are they?
They call themselves the Messengers.
The Twelve.
That's what Peters called them.
They're part of the same organization
that you have been fighting in the past.
They also exist here in my time.
What do they want?
My machine.
They want to travel through time?
For what, I don't know.
Alter history, ensure the plague...
or maybe they just want to
hear Hendrix at Woodstock.
But if they somehow manage to
change something in the past,
then I want to know what it is.
- This will make it...
- So time moves around you.
Good... [laughs] morning, bright eyes.
Uh, we haven't officially met.
I'm Deacon.
Dr. Grim, time to go.
They're ready for you.
Our time has come.
The ashes of yesterday, washed away.
You are prepared.
Your mission is clear.
You are part of the salvation.
[whispering] We will meet again...
in the forest...
when the blood has washed away.
♪ ♪
I think that's your cue.
So where and to when am I to send him?
That is not your concern.
Mr. Rodell, enter the coordinates.
[electronic beeping]
I would reconsider this if I were you.
All considerations have
been made long before.
This will be.
Now, initiate the sequence.
Very well.
♪ ♪
[machine whirring]
[screaming and groaning]
Stop this.
Stop this right now!
She's locked us out.
[screaming and groaning]
Whoa.
[power-down whine]
[tense music]
♪ ♪
[laughing]
So... who's next?
What happened?
She reconfigured the sequence.
She splintered... only part of him.
I warned you.
Fix this.
I can't access the terminal.
She encrypted it.
Ah... uhh!
Unlock the system.
Did you really think I would
just hand over my machine to you?
I guess there's a reason
you call yourselves monkeys.
Go on, kill me.
Come on.
Kill me! Huh?
No, not you.
Your friend, whom you
exhausted yourself to save,
will be executed unless
you unlock the system now.
- Katarina.
- Easy.
You won't do it.
This machine was completed because
we received a message from this woman,
a message she has yet to
send from her own timeline.
You kill her, all of this will be erased.
Your philosophy is still marred by
your simplistic notion of causality.
You still don't understand
the nature of time.
If something is meant to be, it shall be.
This I can prove to you.
Hey!
Interfere again, and
our deal will be revoked.
Painfully.
Stop!
If causality is your religion, madam,
have faith in it.
Unlock the machine.
Katarina...
don't.
♪ ♪
Very well.
- [electronic beeping]
- I got it.
I-I got it.
I bypassed the encryption program.
I located the startup protocol.
Prepare yourself.
Our time has come.
The ashes of yesterday, washed away.
You are prepared.
Your mission is clear.
You are part of the salvation.
[whispering] We will meet again...
in the forest...
when the blood has washed away...
and all things are one.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[whirring, power-up hum]
[power-down whine]
Mother Nature.
We call her that for a reason.
She gave us everything,
we depend on her,
and it is my belief
that she depends on us.
Tampering with this symbiotic relationship
may undo her,
undo ourselves,
and therein lies the rub
with bioengineering.
Thank you. That is all for today.
And thank you for letting
me talk the ears off of you.
[scattered laughter]
[speaking Hungarian]
[students murmuring]
Dr. Kalman?
Just a moment.
Ethan Seki sent me.
Excuse me.
You can tell him...
that I am no longer involved
in that line of work.
He's not with Markridge.
I know who he's with.
I was a poison in that place.
Reshaping life so you can destroy it?
I can't do that to the world.
It knows.
The soul knows.
But you walked away.
Just became a different man.
Better.
Sometimes that's all it takes.
Ramse taught me that.
Yeah, well, now he needs your help.
The 12 Monkeys...
they put something in him,
something that helps them find him.
A tracker device. Sounds like them.
We need you to cut it out.
I don't want to get involved.
- But you will.
- And why is that?
Because you owe him.
We owe something to the
people who make us better.
I can treat him at my office.
No, he's safer underground.
You have to come to us.
Can you do it?
It won't be pretty.
Doesn't have to be.
I once knew a doctor.
She pulled a bullet out of me
using nothing but a pocket knife
and a bottle of vodka from the minibar.
She wasn't just your doctor, was she?
She made me better.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[power-up whine]
I never would have, uh...
That's just a temporary partnership.
Once those guys move out,
me and my boys are moving in.
You're yellow.
I'm sorry?
Your skin.
You know what jaundice is?
Skin coloration caused by
elevated levels of bilirubin.
I, uh...
You've got the shakes, you bruise easily,
and there's a ring in your eyes.
You have Wilson's disease.
Why, Doctor, are you trying to scare me?
You have too much copper in
your liver and your brain.
You're a sick man, aren't you, Deacon?
Nothing I can't handle.
How long before your
boys notice the tremors?
You'll look weak. Not to
mention the inevitable psychosis.
It's fatal if untreated.
You need meds.
Yeah... little hard to come by these days.
Not where I'm from.
A pill a day will keep you healthy.
Help me stop those men,
and I'll go back and get you medicine.
Whoa.
Nice try. Really.
I see what you're trying to do.
You are adorable.
No... no...
30 years ago,
your new friends destroyed the world.
Ever think to ask what they
might be using that machine for?
♪ ♪
No.
We could help each other.
- Uh-huh.
- Think about it.
Shit.
♪ ♪
Ooh.
And there we are.
Subdermal tracker.
That's how they found you, my old friend.
Need you to get it out of me, Ben.
Can't say I'm enamored
with the working conditions,
but you helped me once
get away from that life,
so I am happy to give you another scar.
[chuckles]
Now, perhaps you gentlemen have noticed
that I am not a brave man.
That is why I am halfway across the world,
away from my old life.
I don't like guns.
Makes surgery difficult
if my hands are shaking.
I'll go keep watch.
Here we go.
[groaning]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
There she is.
[metal clatters]
[sighs]
How do you feel?
Can you still feel the pain?
Can you scream?
[grunts]
[breathing hard]
I've injected you with something that
renders your body mostly paralyzed.
I had to get that out
so that I could deliver
you to them personally.
They'll be grateful.
They'll give me protection
against the plague.
It is coming, you know,
in a matter of days.
They're using Leland's daughter, Jennifer.
They never let you in on that, did they?
It's Manhattan.
That's when it starts.
Chinese New Year.
Year of the Monkey.
[chuckles]
Figures.
[gun cocks]
I'm sorry about your friend.
[groaning]
Mr. Cole?
[metal clattering]
[metal jangling]
[gun cocks]
You looking for someone?
[shuddering] Please.
- Please.
- [gun clatters]
[panting]
Your friend's alive.
Your hands shaking now, Doctor?
You're working for them, aren't you?
Yes.
You didn't become anything better.
But I wanted to.
I wanted to.
So did I.
[gunshot]
[panting]
[groans] Ohh...
You all right?
You okay?
♪ ♪
You're free and clear now, brother.
[metal clatters]
He made a deal with them.
Yeah.
What'd he say? Did he know anything?
Nothing.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
[sighs]
Wilson's disease.
Is that a real thing?
Very.
And you can make me better?
I can.
These guys are fast and stupid strong,
so when I grab him,
I want you to put this
six inches into his neck.
Why his neck?
Because he will die quick and quiet.
Let him live, you created an enemy.
♪ ♪
Don't hesitate, don't miss, or we die.
- Clear?
- I'm a doctor.
Believe me when I tell you:
"Do no harm" died 30 years ago.
Oh, boy. She's a real feisty one.
[grunting]
Do it.
Do it!
Damn it, now!
[screams]
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Welcome to the future, Dr. Railly.
What are we doing?
We're gonna need reinforcements,
so I called in some.
Your boys.
My boys.
Honey, meet the West 7.
You guys ready?
Found a soldier scoping out the place.
We grabbed him.
Put a bullet in his head?
No.
Put a gun in his hand.
We need all the help we can get.
Dr. Railly?
Hi.
[shipping horns blow]
Where you gonna go?
I don't know.
Double back.
Keep trying to find the virus.
Look, I'm sorry about all of it.
Your son... I never wanted that.
Take care of yourself, brother.
You too.
[somber music]
♪ ♪
It's New York.
Jennifer Goines has the virus.
Jennifer.
Ben said it was gonna
be the Chinese New Year.
Why you telling me this?
I don't know.
Part of me feels like it's
not gonna make a difference.
You're gonna keep on trying,
and you're gonna get yourself killed.
I just don't want it happening on my watch.
Are we gonna go to New York or what?
[chuckles]
So I'm on your watch now.
Oh, never left.
Except when you stabbed me in '87.
I did.
I got you good.
- _
- [upbeat music]
♪ ♪
- ♪ One pill makes you larger ♪
- [voice whispering indistinctly]
- ♪ And one pill makes you small ♪
- [voice whispers, mutters]
♪ And the ones that Mother gives you ♪
♪ Don't do anything at all ♪
♪ Go ask Alice ♪
♪ When she's ten feet tall ♪
[voice murmuring, laughing]
- [man's voice echoes]
- [music continues]
But more of a thrill-seeker.
You know what I'm saying?
I got a WaveRunner when I turned 40.
I bought a boat when I got divorced,
so you know, got a boat.
Okay, but I'm... I'm doing all the talking.
Why don't you tell me a
little bit about yourself?
What, uh, brings you to
the world of speed dating?
Me?
I'm a this-and-that
kind of girl.
Ten fingers, ten pies.
Potpourri, Russian roulette.
- It's a real mixed bag.
- Hey, right?
Ordinary is boring, right?
I've been walking around a while.
Got a big decision to make.
Oh, man, I know all about those.
- Been down that road.
- Okay.
In that vial are four
very tiny little horsemen:
comets and dinosaurs,
zombies and global warming,
a viral Armageddon that'll make
the Ice Age look like autumn.
Okay, listen, you're hot, right?
But I'm probably just
gonna go find somebody else.
This all...
I got cases of this stuff,
and quite frankly... I
mean, if I'm being frank...
far too many reasons to
use it: poverty, injustice,
man's in humanity towards man, dogfighting.
Dogfighting. Dogfighting.
Okay, listen, for this kind of drama
I could have stuck with online dating
or something like that, all right?
Oh, you paraglide and parasail and midlife
crisis your way through an existence
that was half over before
you were born, but...
but... mmm... you got moxie,
and I like your tie.
So how about this, how about this?
If not in your own story,
I'm gonna give you the chance
to be a hero in somebody else's.
Jesus Christ, lady. Is that a gun?
Shh, shh.
[whispering] Today you can save the world.
All you got to do is pull the trigger.
Right there.
Okay. Pull the trigger.
Come on, do it.
Hey, hey. Do it.
Come on.
Running out of time,
Dale. Come on, just do it.
You're off your rocker.
You're a lunatic.
[bell dings]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
Stock tip: invest heavily
in very deep holes.
♪ ♪
[cell phone dialing]
911. Do you have an emergency?
Yeah, I have an emergency.
Another one's gone through.
We need to hurry.
[power-up whine]
♪ ♪
[grunting]
[groans] They locked us out,
sealed the blast doors from the other side.
That's another one.
We need a plan.
Can you control the power from in here?
- The core? Yeah.
- Question.
You juice that thing, what
happens to the machine?
Well, it would overload.
Take out everything in that room.
What about Jones?
Well, she should get down.
Do it.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[machine whirring]
Core's on overdrive.
[whirring]
[boom]
[overlapping screaming]
[alarm blaring]
[Jones coughing]
[both grunting]
[gunshot]
[coughing]
Marcus?
Are you all right?
Yes.
How many were sent back?
Six.
Oh, my God.
♪ ♪
That'll take time to rebuild.
Months.
Maybe a year.
But I can bring her back to life.
And then what?
The mission will continue.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
[fireworks bursting]
[crowd whooping]
How are we supposed to find her?
She could be anywhere.
[crowd cheering]
This is never gonna work.
We got to split up, cover more ground.
Then what?
We stop her from releasing the virus.
How are we gonna do that?
We do whatever it takes.
- [firecrackers popping]
- [overlapping excited chatter]
[suspenseful music]
♪ ♪
And he's peering from high,
high, high atop the trees.
It's time for him to rise up.
It's the moment of the monkey.
It's the year of the monkey.
It's the year of the monkey!
It's...
Hands off, asshole.
[dramatic music]
♪ ♪
Jennifer!
Cole.
[dramatic music]
Jennifer!
Jennifer... stop!
Wait!
- Jennifer!
- No!
- Wait! Stop!
- Stop!
- No!
Wait, wait, wait.
[humming]
[gasps]
You're gonna stop me.
Finally, someone's gonna stop me.
Thank you for coming for me.
Faith in humanity restored.
Faith in myself, not so much.
Okay, please do it.
Do it.
[suspenseful music]
Jennifer, just give me the virus.
No, Jennifer.
This is your purpose.
Your entire life has led to this moment.
The Witness has spoken.
♪ ♪
[dramatic music]
You can drop it, Mr. Cole.
Shit.
See, you're cursing fate,
but the real tragedy is the
time you waste running from it.
Jennifer, you don't have to do this.
You don't need anyone to stop you.
You have a choice.
This isn't fate.
Spoken from a man who is
somehow able to defy it.
Mr. Ramse was supposed to die.
The Witness had foreseen it.
But you saved Ramse's life.
That changed things.
But this deviation, Mr.
Cole, has run its course.
[gun cocks]
Jennifer... don't do it.
[gunshot]
Oh, my God!
Ah!
Cole.
Cassie?
You need to move out of the way.
What are you doing?
Jones and I, we figured it out in 2044.
'44?
How long were you there?
Eight months.
We found a police report.
A man said he met a woman at a
bar who claimed to have a virus.
It was Jennifer, Cole,
this whole time.
This all ends when she dies.
No, this is a mistake.
They're making her do this.
Cole, you need to move out of the way.
Killing Jennifer is not the answer.
Cole, you need to move.
Now.
Cassie.
Cole, drop it.
Please.
Don't make me do this.
No one's making you do anything.
You have a choice.
So what's it gonna be?
[suspenseful music]
Sync and corrections by explosiveskull
www.addic7ed.com